Wait. Before we go in, I just want you to know that I love you.
等一下，在進屋之前 我要你知道我愛你
I had a great time on our honeymoon.
我蜜月時玩得很高興
I can't wait to spend our life together.
我等不及 要跟你共度一生了
You're sticking with the shell necklace, huh?
你還戴著 那條貝殼項鏈？
You're back!
你們回來了
Come on in!
快進來
How was the honeymoon?
你們蜜月玩得開心嗎？
So much fun. The best part is, we met this great couple.
我們很開心，最棒的是 我們認識一對很棒的夫婦
That was the best part? Good honeymooning, tiger.
那是最棒的嗎？ 這真的是很棒的蜜月，小子
They're cool. It was their honeymoon too.
他們很酷 他們也是去度蜜月的
They live here in the city.
他們就住在城裡
Can we go call them? Is it too soon to call?
我們能打電話給他們嗎？ 現在打會不會太快了？
We're excited. We finally have a couple to hang out with.
我們很興奮 我們終於認識一對夫婦朋友了
Oh, were you looking for that?
你們想要那麼做嗎？
Well, yeah.
對
A couple? Like two people? Like one, two people?
夫婦朋友？你是說兩個人嗎？ 像是一、二，兩個人
It's different. Greg and Jenny are married.
那不一樣 葛瑞格跟珍妮結婚了
Greg and Jenny? "Hi, Greg. I'm Chandler."
葛瑞格跟珍妮？ 「嗨，葛瑞格，我是錢德」
"Hi, Monica. This is Jenny." "Hi, Jenny. Hi, Greg."
「嗨，摩妮卡，她是珍妮」 「嗨，珍妮，嗨，摩妮卡」
-They're great. If you just.. -You know what?
-他們真的很棒，如果你們… -你知道嗎？
Give us our souvenirs and get out of here.
快送我們紀念品 然後滾出去
-We didn't get a chance to.. -You're kidding!
-我們沒有機會… -你是在開玩笑
-We didn't get anything for anyone. -Nice necklace.
-我們沒有買任何人的禮物 -好漂亮的項鏈
That you can have.
你可以把它拿走
The One With The Videotape
本集播出：錄影帶風波
rainystr壓制iPod-MP4
-Welcome home. -How was the honeymoon?
-歡迎你們回來 -蜜月還好玩吧？
Great! How about you? You're having a baby!
太棒了，你們呢？ 你們要有寶寶了
Yeah, we are. It's so exciting.
沒錯，那真的很刺激
I always knew you two would have a child out of wedlock.
我就知道 你們會未婚生子
-Look, I have a sonogram picture. -Good.
-你看，我有寶寶的超音波照片 -太棒了
Ross, it's got your wavy, black lines.
羅斯，寶寶遺傳了你的黑色卷髮
Now that Ross knows, how'd it happen? When? How many times?
現在羅斯知道了，到底是怎麼發生的？ 在什麼時候？你們做了幾次？
Monica, that's not right. Start with where.
摩妮卡，那麼問是不對的 從你們在哪裡做開始說吧
It happened about six weeks ago.
事情發生在六個星期前
I got home and Ross was there. He'd been hanging out with Joey.
我回到家，發現羅斯也在 他跟喬伊混在一起
You're welcome, buddy.
別客氣，兄弟
Yeah, thanks.
對，謝謝
I had a lot of work, and Ross offered to help.
我有很多事要做 羅斯主動說要幫忙
We had wine, we got to talking.
我們邊喝酒邊聊天
Next thing you know, Ross comes on to me.
接下來 羅斯採取主動
That's a little misleading.
那麼說是不對的
-What is? -The lie you just told.
-什麼？ -你剛剛說的謊話
-That you came on to me? -There's the one!
-我說是你主動的？ -沒錯
-But you did. Let's be honest. -Yes, let's.
-但那是真的，老實一點吧 -沒錯，老實一點吧
Ross. If it helps, I don't believe you.
羅斯，希望這有幫助，我不相信你
It's not important.
那不重要
What's important is, we're having a baby, not who came on to who.
重要的是我們要生孩子了 誰先泡「隨」並不重要
"Whom."
是「誰」才對
That's right.
沒錯
-You kissed me first. -You were begging for it!
-你先吻我的 -是你求我的
You were sending me signals!
你發暗號給我
I was sending signals? Anyone think that I'd send Ross begging signals?
我發暗號給你？ 誰覺得是我發暗號給羅斯求他的？
Please, show of hands.
請舉手
It doesn't matter what people believe! It happened.
別人怎麼想並不重要 事情真的發生了
Maybe I need to be more careful. Am I sending these signals now?
或許我得小心一點 我正在發送訊號嗎？
-You know what? Just drop it. -Show me how I begged you.
-你知道嗎？別談了 -告訴我我是怎麼求你的
I can show you! I have it on videotape.
我可以證明 我都錄在錄影帶裡了
It's an expression.
那是一種說法
Come on, Rachel, open up. Let me explain.
瑞秋，快開門 聽我解釋
-Still won't let you in, huh? -No.
-她還是不讓你進去？ -對
I'm just gonna close this door so we can talk about you.
我要把門關上 我們得好好討論你們的事
I can't believe he taped them having sex.
我不敢相信 他錄下他們做愛的經過
Yeah. You gotta tell a girl before you tape her.
對，你得先告訴對方 才能開始錄影
Such a rookie mistake.
那是菜鳥才會犯的錯誤
-Know who has a great camera? -Greg and Jenny?
-你知道誰有很棒的攝影機嗎？ -葛瑞格跟珍妮？
-I want to call them. -Let's call.
-我要打電話給他們 -快打吧
Ask them if they brought their friends souvenirs.
問他們有沒有 買紀念品送給朋友
Hello. 8th Street Deli?
喂，第八街外送餐廳
Hang up. You get food poisoning just talking to that place.
快掛掉，光跟他們說話 你就會食物中毒
-Sorry, wrong number. -Here you go, babe.
-抱歉，打錯了 -來吧，寶貝
Hello? It's the deli again!
喂 又是外送餐廳
All right, I'll have a sandwich.
好吧，我要吃三明治
I don't think this number's right.
我想這個電話號碼是錯的
-What? -You got fake-numbered.
-什麼？ -你們拿到假的電話
-What? People don't do that. -Oh, I think we do.
-什麼？沒有人會那麼做 -我想我們會
-Why would they do that? -I don't know.
-他們為什麼要那麼做？ -我不知道
You were a delight. You asked those great questions.
你們聊的很開心 你問了那些很棒的問題
And you were never funnier. Joke, joke, joke! You were a hoot!
你也很風趣 老是在開玩笑，你真的很耍寶
You still got me and Phoebe.
你們還有我跟菲比
Excuse me, I don't want Greg and Jenny's rejects.
對不起 我不要葛瑞格跟珍妮的退貨
Rachel won't talk to me. She won't open the door.
瑞秋不肯跟我說話 她不肯開門
I wonder why, pervert.
我很好奇是為什麼，變態
Okay, I am not a pervert.
好吧，我不是變態
That's, like, the pervert motto.
變態都是那麼說的
You raise your hand, put your left hand down your pants and repeat that.
你舉起手，把左手放進褲子裡 然後再說一次
Filming Rachel was not planned.
我不是故意要拍瑞秋
Here's what happened. Joey can back me up.
事情的經過是這樣的 喬伊可以幫我作證
A month and a half ago, remember I came to you with a problem?
還記得一個半月前 我跑去問你一個問題嗎？
The personal thing?
我的私人問題？
-What personal thing? -About sex?
-什麼私人問題？ -關於性的問題？
That I hadn't had sex in months?
我好幾個月沒有性生活了？
Yeah, I knew what you were talking about.
我知道 你在說什麼
（六個星期前）
I'd like to talk about something I'm uncomfortable talking about.
我想談一件 我很難啟齒的事
Sure.
沒問題
How about you showering with your mom?
你跟你媽 一起洗澡？
I actually had a topic in mind.
我真的有問題
I'm kind of going through a dry spell, sex-wise.
我正進入了 性停滯期
-For, like, months? -Five, to be..
-有好幾個月了嗎？ -五個月…
lying. Six.
騙人的，是六個月
Six months? That's rough.
六個月？那一定很難熬
It's not all bad. I'm learning to appreciate the small things, like..
沒有那麼糟糕 我學著去欣賞一些小事，譬如說…
the sound of a bird and the color of the sky.
鳥叫聲 跟天空的顏色
The sky's blue, Ross. And I had sex yesterday.
天空是藍色的，羅斯 我昨天做過愛了
Please help me. I have a date tonight.
拜託幫幫我 今晚我有約會
It has to go well. I'm scared for my health.
我得順利達陣 我很擔心我的健康
I got something. It's this story that I came up with.
我有個點子 我想出一個故事
Very romantic. Any woman that hears it is putty.
非常浪漫 聽到這個故事的女人都會心動
Tell it to me.
說吧
Now, you're gonna want to have sex with me when you hear it.
你聽完後 一定會想跟我上床
Remember, it is just the story.
記住，那只是一個故事
I'll try to control myself.
我會試著控制自己
Years ago, I was backpacking across Western Europe..
多年前 我在西歐自助旅行…
-You were backpacking across Europe? -Have a nice six more months.
-你在西歐自助旅行？ -六個月後見
I'm sorry. Please, please. You were in Western Europe, and..?
抱歉，求求你 你去了西歐，然後…
I was outside Barcelona, hiking in the foothills of Mount Tibidabo.
我在巴塞隆納郊外 在第比達包山腳下健行
-Nice. -Thanks.
-太棒了 -謝謝
I was at the end of this path, and there was a lake.
我走到小路的盡頭 發現了一座湖
Very secluded. There were tall trees all around.
它非常隱密 四周都是高大的樹木
It was dead silent. Gorgeous.
那裡非常安靜 美極了
And across the lake I saw a beautiful woman bathing herself.
我看到在湖的對面 有個美女在洗澡
But she was crying.
但她在哭
Why?
為什麼？
This is great wine.
酒真的很棒
It's from France.
它是法國酒
In Europe.
法國在歐洲
Western Europe.
就在西歐
A few years ago I was backpacking across Western Europe.
幾年前 我在西歐自助旅行
-Really? -Wait, it gets better.
-真的嗎？ -等一下，後面的故事很精彩
Yeah, I was in Barcelona.
對，我在巴塞隆納
I studied for a year in Barcelona.
我在巴塞隆納念過一年書
-You did? -Yeah. When were you there?
-是嗎？ -對，你什麼時候去的？
-Eighty.. -Nine?
-8… -89年？
Three.
83年
I was 13?
那時我才13歲？
-So anyway, I was hiking.. -I love hiking!
-總之我在健行… -我喜歡健行
That's great!
那真的太棒了
I was hiking along the foothills of Mount Tibidaybo..
我在第比達亞波山腳下 健行…
-I think it's "Tibidabo." -Do you want to tell the story?
-我想是「第比達包山」才對 -你想說這個故事嗎？
How'd your date go?
約會還順利嗎？
Great. I'm across the street having sex right now.
太棒了 我正要過街去做愛
-Your story sucks. -Then you didn't tell it right.
-你的故事爛透了 -是你說的方法不對
-Show me how you did it. -No, I don't want to.
-告訴我你是怎麼說的 -不，我不想談
-How long since you seen a girl naked? -I was backpacking..
-你上次看到裸女是什麼時候的事？ -我在西歐…
-I'm not feeling it. -I was outside Barcelona, hiking..
-我沒有感覺 -我在巴塞隆納郊外健行…
-Ross, I'm not hot. Are you hot? -It's been six months. I'm always hot.
-羅斯，我不熱，你很熱嗎？ -我六個月沒做愛，每天都很熱
You're not selling the story. You don't believe it.
你不是在說故事 你根本就不相信它
I gotta go, I got a date. But try this.
我得走了，我有約會 但試試這招
Do what I do before an audition.
學我在試鏡前做的那一招
I'm not hungry.
我不餓
No.
不
Use my camera to record yourself and see what you're doing wrong.
我會用錄影機來自拍 看看哪裡做錯了
I'll try that.
我會試試看
Now, you're all set up. Good to go. Just hit record. Good luck.
已經設定好了，可以拍了 按下錄影鍵就可以了，祝你好運
If you ever have any problem with the ladies, you know I'll help you out.
如果你跟女人約會出了問題 我可以幫你接手
That means a lot to me, man.
那對我來說意義重大
Can I get you anything? Lens cleaner? Your battery okay?
需要我幫你效勞嗎？ 要擦鏡頭嗎？電池還有電嗎？
Ross, thank God you're here. You have to help me.
羅斯，謝天謝地你在這裡 你得幫我
Were you talking to yourself?
你在自言自語嗎？
That's less embarrassing. Yes. Yes, I was.
那會比較不丟臉 對，沒錯
When she came in, I totally forgot about the camera.
她一走進來 我完全忘記錄影機的事
It kept rolling and recorded everything.
錄影機一直在拍 錄下了整個經過
Yeah, we're gonna need to see that tape.
我們得看看 那卷錄影帶
What a great idea! That'll get Rachel to forgive me.
那是個好主意 那會讓瑞秋原諒我
Come on, it'll be like watching the Discovery Channel..
少來了，那就像是在看 探索頻道…
only we'll know the monkeys.
只不過我們知道那兩隻猴子是誰
Look, I'm not gonna let you guys watch us.
聽著 我不會讓你們看我們的性愛錄影帶
-I haven't even seen it yet. -I'll trade you two tapes of me having sex.
-我自己都沒有看過 -我可以用我的兩卷錄影帶跟你換
Thanks, I'm good.
謝謝，我很感激
We don't wanna see the dirty stuff..
我們不是要看性愛畫面…
-just the stuff leading up to it. -No. Rachel's gonna kill me as it is.
-我們只想知道事情是怎麼發生的 -不，瑞秋會殺了我的
It's not fair to her. Let's forget the tape.
那對她來說不公平 忘了錄影帶的事吧
Thank you.
謝謝
-No. -You're right.
-不 -你說的對
-Joey, no. -Loud and clear.
-喬伊，不 -我瞭解
I don't get why they'd give us a fake number.
我不明白為什麼 他們要給我們假的電話號碼
If they knew what they were doing, they didn't give you real names.
如果他們知道自己在做什麼 他們不會給你們真名
Maybe people give out fake numbers, but not fake names.
或許有人會給假電話號碼 但沒有人會給假名
Hi. Ken Adams. Nice to meet you.
嗨，肯亞當斯 很高興能認識你
Regina Phalange.
蕾吉娜菲拉吉
-We didn't do anything wrong. -I know.
-我們沒有做錯事 -我知道
Although you did tell an awful lot of jokes.
雖然你說了 很多冷笑話
You said they were funny. Joke, joke, joke!
你說它們很好笑 快說笑話吧
Joke, joke..
說笑話…
-It was your questions. -What about them?
-是你問了太多問題害的 -我的問題怎麼了？
The sheer volume. It was like flying with the Riddler.
你問了太多問題 那像是跟謎題王坐在一起
-Was that another joke? -Was that another question?
-那也是笑話嗎？ -那也是問題嗎？
Is Ross still here?
羅斯還在嗎？
Watch out, honey. Someone else is asking questions now.
小心點，甜心 有人在問問題了
No, but he told us what happened. It was an honest mistake.
不，但他告訴我們發生了什麼事 那真的是個誤會
How would you like it if I had sex with you and I taped it?
如果我把我跟你做愛的過程錄下來 你會有什麼感覺呢？
Oh, forget it.
算了吧
There he is, the father of my child, the porn king of the West Village.
他來了，我孩子的爹 西村的色情片之王
It was an accident, okay?
那是個意外，行嗎？
I feel bad. I swear, I didn't even watch it.
我覺得很難過 我發誓我還沒有看過它
Anyway, here.
總之，拿去吧
You might be more comfortable destroying it yourself.
或許親手毀了它 你會覺得舒服一點
Thank you.
謝謝
What?
什麼？
-You don't want to see this, do you? -Hell, yeah!
-你們不想看這玩意吧？ -我們當然想
I am not gonna show you this.
我不會讓你們看這個
Not the sex part. Just the stuff leading up to it.
我們不是要看性愛鏡頭 只是想看你們怎麼開始的
Forget it.
算了，讓她毀掉吧
We'll think of another way to put the "who came on to who" thing to rest.
我們會想其他辦法 解決「誰先主動」的問題
Come on now, think!
快想
It's Rachel's tape, and she can do whatever she wants.
那是瑞秋的錄影帶 她想怎麼處置它是她的自由
And she wants to destroy it, so end of story.
她想毀了它 別說了
-I want to see it. -What?
-我想看 -什麼？
You don't want us to see this.
你不希望我們看錄影帶
You so badly don't want us to see it that it makes me want to see it.
你不希望我們看它 讓我想要看個究竟
Are we watching the tape or not?
我們到底要不要看錄影帶？
-It's for your sake. -I don't believe you.
-我是要保護你 -我不相信你
I think you don't want them to see you begging me.
我想你不希望 他們看到你求我
-Rachel, please? -Oh, a little preview.
-瑞秋，拜託 -這是預告部份
Fine. I want the record to show that I tried to take the high road.
好吧，我要這卷錄影帶 證明我是想保護你
Because in about five minutes, I'm gonna be saying..
因為再過五分鐘 我會說…
Okay, here we go.
好吧，要開始了
I'm so happy.
我好快樂
Thank God you're here. Help me. Were you talking to yourself?
謝天謝地你在這裡，快幫幫我 你是在自言自語嗎？
-There I am. -You're gonna get pregnant.
-我出現了 -你就要懷孕了
I screwed up so bad.
我搞砸了
I told Monica that I'd send those wedding invitations weeks ago.
好幾個星期前我告訴摩妮卡 我會把喜帖寄出去
You didn't do it?
你沒有寄？
I put them in my desk at work, and forgot about them until today.
我把它們放在辦公桌上 直到今天才想起來
Sweetie, it's okay. Everybody made it to the wedding. I'm fine.
甜心，沒關係的 客人都來了，我沒事的
-Kind of hurting my hand though. -I know.
-但你把我的手弄痛了 -我知道
I can 't believe it, especially after Monica went on and on about it.
我不敢相信 何況摩妮卡每天都在盯我
"Here are the invitations, Rachel. Be very careful, Rachel.
喜帖在這裡，瑞秋 小心點，瑞秋
Please, drinking no liquids around the invitations, Rachel."
拜託，別在喜帖附近 喝東西，瑞秋
Did you do it on our invitations?
你們在我們的喜帖上面做愛？
Not on the ones we sent out.
我們沒在寄出去的喜帖上做
So just the ones you gave back to us and we had framed?
你們在我們拿去裱框 剩下來的喜帖上面做愛？
It seems like yesterday they just got engaged.
感覺上像是 他們昨天才訂婚
I know.
我知道
Remember the night they got engaged? How you and I almost..
還記得他們訂婚那一晚嗎？ 你跟我差一點…
Oh, I remember how we almost.
我記得我們差一點就做了
You think we would've gone through with it?
你覺得 我們真的會做嗎？
You think we would have done it?
你覺得我們會做嗎？
I know I wanted to. I just wasn 't sure if you did.
我知道我想做 但我不知道你要不要
Oh, I wanted to.
我也想
So we both wanted to.
那麼我們兩個都想
Interesting.
真有趣
Anyway, it probably worked out for the best.
總之這樣的結果 或許是最好的
Yeah, sure.
沒錯
In about 10 seconds, he kisses me.
再過十秒他就要吻我了
In about 5 seconds, you'll see why.
再過五秒你們就會知道為什麼
Did I ever tell you about the time I backpacked through Western Europe?
我有沒有跟你說過 我到西歐自助旅行的事？
Get ready to see some begging.
準備看她求我吧
-Oh, you came on to Ross! -What?
-是你對羅斯主動的 -什麼？
Now I'm so happy.
現在我好快樂
-What? -You used the Europe story!
-什麼？ -你用了歐洲的故事
That's the magic story you use when you want to have sex!
那是你想做愛時 會用的魔法故事
-How do you know about that story? -How do you know about that story?
-你怎麼知道那個故事？ -你怎麼知道那個故事？
My friend Irene heard it from some guy.
是一個傢伙 告訴我朋友艾琳的
Some guy!
就是我
No, she told me that his name was Ken Adams.
不，她說那個傢伙 叫做肯亞當斯
Ken Adams!
我是肯亞當斯
So, people are familiar with the Europe story?
大家都知道 歐洲的故事？
About that, the "who came on to who" thing really doesn't matter.
關於「誰主動」的問題 那真的不重要
It would have happened either way.
反正結果圓滿就好了
If you hadn't initiated it, I know I would have.
你說的對 我知道我很快樂
-It was an amazing night. -It was. It was amazing.
-那是個神奇的夜晚 -沒錯，它很神奇
You think it looked amazing?
你覺得它看起來會很神奇嗎？
I don't know. I honestly didn't watch it.
我不知道 我真的沒看
Yeah, me neither.
對，我也沒看
Yet.
我還沒有看
-That may be weird. -Yeah, it would be really weird.
-那應該會很奇怪 -對，它真的很奇怪
-Good luck. -Good luck to you.
-祝你好運 -祝你好運
-Mind if I mute? -Oh, please.
-我可以消音嗎？ -麻煩你了
-There go the clothes. -You are undressing awfully quickly.
-我們開始脫衣服了 -你脫衣服的速度真快
Six months, Rachel. Six months.
我六個月沒做了，瑞秋
-We look pretty good. -I was gonna say.
-我們看起來很不錯 -我也那麼認為
-Nice tan. -Thank you.
-你的皮夫曬得很漂亮 -謝謝
I'd just gone to the beach that weekend.
那個週末 我才去過海邊
-Have you been working out? -I have been working out.
-你有在健身嗎？ -我一直在健身
This is so much better than I ever..
這比我之前的經驗 要好得多了…
Oh, that's not pretty.
那真的很難看
-Make it stop. Make it stop. -Oh, no!
-快停下來 -不
Greg and Jenny's number is totally different in here.
葛瑞格跟珍妮的電話號碼 完全不一樣
-I don't ask too many questions, do I? -No.
-我沒有問太多問題嗎？ -沒有
-Really? -Absolutely not.
-真的嗎？ -絕對沒有
-Really? -Oh, God.
-真的？ -天啊
I bet that phone thing was some sort of mix-up. I'm gonna call them.
我敢說電話號碼的事是個誤會 我要打電話給他們
Hello, Greg? This is Monica from the plane.
喂，葛瑞格嗎？ 我是飛機上跟你們見過面的摩妮卡
Listen, the number that you gave me,8-5-3..
聽著，你給我的電話號碼 853…
Jenny's been giving out their old number!
珍妮老是給別人 他們的舊電話號碼
Jenny! That is so Jenny!
那真的很像珍妮的作風
How would you like to get together next Saturday?
你們下星期六 要跟我們一起去玩嗎？
Okay, how about Sunday?
好吧，星期天呢？
Okay, the week after that?
下星期呢？
The week after that?
下下星期呢？
You know what? We are interesting, funny people with good questions.
你知道嗎？ 我們是很會問問題的幽默大師
And if you and your precious Jenny can't see that..
如果你跟你的寶貝珍妮 不能瞭解…
January 15?
一月十五日？
We'll see you then!
到時候見